

Contact Details

Pablo Ibieta CPF 236.705.918-40

ibieta.pablo@gmail.com pibieta@if.usp.br

(+55) 11 959 410 565

Work Address

Rua do Matão Travessa R Nr. 187, Off. 331 CEP 05508-090 São Paulo, Brazil.

Personal Address

Rua Frei Inácio da Conceição 237, Apto 6 CEP 05362-040 São Paulo, Brazil.

Details and Publications

Curriculo Lattes

https://bit.ly/2CXGU8i

in/pibieta

7/pibieta

Languages

Spanish: Mother tongue

English: Fluent Portuguese: Fluent

French: Basic

Pablo Ibieta

Physicist

About me Since 2012, I have worked as a scientific researcher in the area of Quantum Physics. During this period, I have acquired advanced mathematical knowledge and learned several computational skills concerning data analysis. This involves the manipulation and interpretation of data and the use of statistical tools to compare data to models. In order to complement these skills, currently I am focused on the study and development of Python based Data Science and Machine Learning tools.

Experience

Sep 2012 - present

Junior Researcher and Teaching Assistant, Instituto de Física, Universidade de São Paulo (USP). São Paulo, Brazil. Research projects include:

- Topological phases of matter, quantum physics and mathematical physics.
- Computer vision for astrophysical image classification.
- NLP and Deep Learning for ChatBots, both retrieval and generative.

Oct 2018 - present

Kaggle Competitions participant: New York City Taxi Fare Predictions and Predict Future Sales

Jan 2018

Visiting Professor, Universidad Mayor de San Andrés, Physics Department. La Paz, Bolivia.

Sep 2005 - Feb 2010

Junior Researcher and Teaching Assistant. Institute for Theoretical Physics, UMSA, Physics Department. La Paz, Bolivia.

Education

2015 - 2019

Ph. D. in Physics, Universidade de São Paulo (USP). São Paulo, Brazil.

2012 - 2015

M. Sc. in Physics, Universidade de São Paulo (USP) São Paulo, Brazil.

2004 - 2010

Bachelor in Physics, Universidad Mayor de San Andrés (UMSA). La Paz, Bolivia.

Skills

Technical

Machine Learning, Neural Networks, Simulations, Feature Engineering, Data Analysis, Visualization, Web.

Software Development

Python, R, C, C++, Mathematica, SQL, NoSQL, HTML, CSS.

Numpy, Pandas, seaborn, matplotlib, openCV, nltk, spacy, Flask, Django, Tensorflow, Keras, sklearn and XGBoost.